Misch, Carl; Papers ger067
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Carl Misch Papers
1941-1963
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Misch, Carl, 1896-1965
ger067
0.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence in German, 194162; and typescripts of articles and lectures, in German and English, on Germany, Paris, prominent individuals, and other topics, 194563.
Biographical History
Carl Misch was a German journalist who immigrated to the United States, via France during the Second World War. Misch was a journalist and historian and taught history at Centre College.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence in German, 194162; and typescripts of articles and lectures, in German and English, on Germany, Paris, prominent individuals, and other topics, 194563.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series, arranged chronologically.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Mrs. Carl Misch. 1974
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Literature; Correspondence; Misch, Carl, 1896-1965; Tillich, Paul, 1886-1965; Eyck, Erich, 1878-1964
- Bergstraesser, Arnold, (1 L. to Misch, 1 L. by Misch), 1948 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 1)
- Bermann-Fischer, Gottfried, (5 L. to Misch), 1947-1948 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 2)
- Budzislawski, Hermann, (3 L. to Misch, 4 L. by Misch), 1941 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 3)
- Dombrowski, Erich, (3 L. to Misch, 3 L. by Misch), 1947 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 4)
- Eyck, Erich, (5 L. to Misch), 1949-1961 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 5)
- Fischer-Baling, Eugen, (1 L. to Misch, 2 photos), 1949 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 6)
- Heuss, Theodor (2 L. to Misch), 1952; 1962 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 7)
- Hirsch, Rudolf (1 L. to Misch, 1 L. by Misch), 1949 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 8)
- Kiaulehn, Walter (2 L. to Misch, 1 L. by Misch, 2 clippings about Kiaulehn), Undated; 1946 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 9)
- Maass, Joachim (1 L., 1 Ptc. to Misch), 1947 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 10)
- Marck, Siegfried (6 L. to Misch, 1 L. by Misch), 1947-1948 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 11)
- Noth, Ernst Erich (3 L. to Misch), 1958-1959 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 12)
- Osborn, Max (1 poem, with short note to Misch), Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 13)
- Schwerin, Kurt (2 L. to Misch), 1957; 1959 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 14)
- Staudinger, Else (7 L. to Misch, 3 L. by Misch), 1948-1961; 1947-1948 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 15)
- Sternfeld, Wilhelm (1 L. to Misch), 1961 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 16)
- Tergit, Gabriele (1 L. to Misch), 1958 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 17)
- Tillich, Paul (1 L. to Misch), 1959 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 18)
- Valentin, Veit (2 L. to Misch, 2 L. to Misch from Liane Valentin, 3 newspaper clippings about Valentin), 1947 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 19)
- Victor, Walther (4 L. to Misch), 1945-1948 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 20)
- Wallenberg, Hans (3 L. to Misch), 1958; 1961 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 21)
- Weichmann, Herbert (3 L. to Misch), 1951; 1965 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 22)
- Weil, Bruno (1 L. to Misch), 1942 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 23)
- Wolff, Richard (1 L. to Misch, 1 L. by Misch), 1955 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 24)
- Zoff, Otto (1 L. to Misch), 1954 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous correspondence A-Z (10 L. to Misch, 18 L. by Misch), Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 26)
- "Der alte Rockefeller Junior. Amerikanische Namensbrauche," 2p., 1953 December 13 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 27)
- "Berlin." Lecture given, University of Kentucky, Student Univ. Music Room, Lexington, Kentucky, Another version. Undated. T. with h. corr. 18p. 29. "Camp Cambronne." T.cc. 5p., 1962 February 10 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 28)
- "Deutschland 1945. 11. An Truemmerstaetten und Werkbaenken." Mimeo. Feuilleton. Foreign Language Features, 7p., Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 29)
- "Deutschlands Schicksal." Vortrag, gehalten im New World Club, Empire Hotel, New York, am. T. with numerous h. corr. 29p., 1946 January 16 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 30)
- "The Downfall of the Weimar Republic." T. with h. corr. 19p., Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 31)
- "Erich Marcks [gestorbenj." T. with some h. corr. 7p., Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 32)
- "Geschichte des deutschen Zeitungswesens." Dated. T. With h. corr. 15p., 1962 November 7 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 33)
- "Lieber tot als Refugie." A. lp., Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 34)
- "Den Maerzgefallnen. Zum hundertsten Gedenktag des 18. Maerz 1848." T. cc. 3p., 1848 March 18 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 35)
- "Ossietzky." Dated 4. V. 1963. T. with h. corr. 16p. - "Ossietzky zum 25. Todestag." Later version. T. 12p. (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 36)
- "Pressefreiheit in U.S.A." Dated Sept. 7, 1951. T. with some h. corr. 10p., 1951 September 7 (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 37)
- "This is Paris today. Report of an eye-witness." Edited by Carl Misch. T.cc. with some h. corr. 22p., Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 38)
- Veit Valentin." T. with h. corr. 2c. 23p. ea. 1 p. notes., Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 39)
- Untitled Ms. English text. T. 4p Untitled Ms. German text. T: lp., Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 40)
- Articles by Misch. 12 clippings, Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 41)
- clippings about Misch, Misch's works. 5 items, Undated (Box 1 (Carl Misch Papers), Folder 42)